Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Don Robertson Papers, 1978-1985 RL.11124
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company. Don Robertson papers, 1978-1985
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
J. Walter Thompson Company
RL.11124
1.5 Linear Feet
Established in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. Don Robertson was an executive who served with JWT's Canadian and Australian offices as well as Thompson Recruitment.
Arrangement
Arranged alphabetically.
Biographical / Historical
Don Robertson served as Account Supervisor, JWT Montreal (1965); Vice President, Account Services, JWT Montreal (1967); President and CEO, JWT Canada, Toronto (1971); Chairman, JWT Australia (1977); Executive Vice President, JWT Corporate Development (1980); Chief Planning Officer, JWT NY (1980-1985); President and CEO, Thompson Recruitment (1985-circa 1987); retired 1989.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company. Don Robertson papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1987.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following J. Walter Thompson Company Collections: Don Johnston Papers; Herbert Eames Papers.
Collection Overview
Collection spans 1978-1985 and includes administrative, financial and research reports, publications, conference notes, policy manuals and other printed materials. Materials chiefly concern JWT operations in Canada and the United States. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Advertising -- United States; Advertising -- Canada; Advertising agencies -- Canada; Advertising agencies -- United States; Advertising executives -- United States; J. Walter Thompson Company
- Acquisitions file, 1980-1982; 2 folders (Box 1)
- Advertising ban for alcohol, 1978-1985 (Box 1)
- Agency performance evaluation, 1981 (Box 1)
- Cable Capsules, 1982 (Box 1)
- Enterprise Advertising Associates (Canada), 1980-1984; 3 folders (Box 1)
- European Managers Meeting, 1981; 2 folders (Box 2)
- General Manager development, 1983 (Box 2)
- JWT Group Communication Services: A Case for a New Growth Perspective (Don Johnston, Herbert Eames), 1981 (Box 2)
- JWT Group growth statement, 1982 (Box 2)
- JWT Group objectives, 1981 (Box 2)
- JWT Group succession, 1981-1983 (Box 2)
- JWT Group Troutbeck conference, 1981 (Box 2)
- Growth for New Business (Jack Cronin), 1980 (Box 2)
- Human Resources meeting, 1979 (Box 2)
- JWT brand names, 1980-1984 (Box 2)
- JWT Group acquisition statement, 1982 (Box 2)
- JWT Group Troutbeck conference, 1981-1983 (Box 3)
- JWT growth statement, 1982 (Box 3)
- JWT West overview, 1982 (Box 3)
- Management incentive plans, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
- Management succession, 1984 (Box 3)
- Nationalism, 1984-1985 (Box 3)
- New Business Manual, 1985 (Box 3)
- Regional Managers study, 1984 (Box 3)
- Research, 1980-1982 (Box 3)
- Research as a Profit Center, 1981 (Box 3)
- Things We Have Learned About Employee Attitude Surveys, 1981 (Box 3)
- Thompson Partners (Bill Sharfman), 1983-1984 (Box 3)